Falguni Vasoya

D-72/1, Surajit Society,
Opp. Hingalaj Temple,
India Colony,
Bapunagar, Ahmedabad-382350
(m) +91 9960240328
falgunigajera37@gmail.com

RESUME SUMMARY

Experienced and accomplished in different skills with different role like delivering lecture in various pharma subjects as an Assistant Professor, successful delivery of research project as a Research Fellow and Medicine dispensing work as a Pharmacist with total 6 years of experience.

SKILLS

Analytical abilities : HPLC, HPTLC, UV

Teaching : Pharmaceutical Analysis, Biochemistry, Biopharmaceutics

Others : ADME studies, QA/QC, Dispensing of Medicine

Documentation : PCI, AICTE and ISO certification audit

EXPERIENCE

1. General Hospital, Sola, Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India

Dec 2013 - March 2015

Pharmacist

Responsibilities:

- Medicine dispensing, Stock management
- 2. B. V. Patel PERD Research Centre, Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India

Sept 2012 - July 2013

Junior Research Fellow

Project: "Pharmacokinetic study of Herbal Drugs" – This is achieved using ADME profile, *In-vitro* metabolism study using liver microsomes and Identification of metabolism using GCMS. Development of validation method is done using HPLC.

3. S. J. Thakkar Pharmacy College, Rajkot, Gujarat, India

July 2008 - April 2012

Assistant Professor

Responsibilities:

- Lectureship in Biopharmaceutics, Biochemistry and Quality Analysis subjects
- Handle practical lab for Biochemistry and Quality Analysis subjects
- Guide M.Pharm students for their thesis work
- Document preparation for PCI, AICTE and ISO certification audit

INDUSTRIAL TRAINING

ESPEE Formulation Pvt. Ltd., Rajkot, Gujarat, India
 QC Trainee – Learned the different aspects of Tablet/Capsule manufacturing process and Quality control process.

EDUCATION

- M. Pharm (Pharmacognosy) with 80.00% (Distinction)
 MCOPS, Manipal University, Karnataka, India
 Thesis: Pharmacognostical, Phytochemical and Hypolipidemic activity of Phyllanthus reticulatus Poir.
- B. Pharm with 71.31% (Distinction)
 Rofel college of Pharmacy, Vapi, V.N.S.G.U, Surat, Gujarat, India
- 3. **H.S.C.** with 75.85% (Distinction) April 2002 G.S.H.S.E.B., Gandhinagar, Gujarat, India
- 4. **S.S.C.** with 85.86%. (Distinction) March 2000 G.S.E.B., Gandhinagar, Gujarat, India

PUBLICATION

- 1. Aswatha Ram H.N., Shreedhara C.S., Falguni Gajera P. and Sachin Zanwar B., "Antioxidant studies of aqueous extract of *Phyllanthus reticulatus* Poir", Pharmacologyonline, Jan-Apr 2008, Vol. 1, 351-364.
- 2. Aswatha Ram H. N.*, Shreedhara C.S., Falguni P. Gajera and Sachin B. Zanwar., In Vitro Free Radical Scavenging Potential of Methanol Extract of Entire Plant of *Phyllanthus reticulatus* Poir", Pharmacologyonline, May-August 2008, Vol. 2, 440- 451.
- 3. Aswatha Ram H.N., Shreedhara C.S., Falguni Gajera P. and Sachin Zanwar B., "Pharmacognostical Evaluation of *Phyllanthus reticulatus* Poir." Pharmacognosy Magazine, Apr-Jun 2009, 4(18): 176-182.
- 4. Dharmishtha A. M., Mishra S. H. and Falguni P. G., "Antioxidant studies of methanolic extract of *Randia dumatorum* Lam." Pharmacologyonline 1: 22-34 (2009).
- 5. Gajera Falguni P., Movalia Dharmishtha A. and Gajera Keyur P., "Quantitation of Rutin in Methanolic Leaf Extract of *Phyllanthus reticulates* Poir. by High Performance Thin Layer Chromatography." international Journal of pharmacy research and development, July-2009 / Volume 1 / Article No 1.
- 6. Movalia Dharmishtha A, Mishra Shri Hari. H. and Gajera Falguni P., "preliminary Pharmacognostic and Physicochemical evaluation of Leaf of *Randia dumetorum* Lamk.". Journal of pharmacy research, 2009, 2(7), 1212-1213.
- 7. Movalia Dharmishtha and Gajera Falguni, "Antibacterial activity of Methanolic fruit extract of *Randia dumetorum* Lamk.", International Journal of PharmTech Research, July-Sept 2009, 1(3), 679-681.
- 8. Shreedhara C.S., Aswatha Ram H.N., Gajera P Falguni, Sachin B Zanwar, Phytochemical and Physico-chemical screening of *Phyllanthus reticulatus* Poir. Aryavaidyan, Feb-Apr 2009, Vol. XXII, No.3, 173-179.
- 9. Shreedhara C.S., Aswatha Ram H.N., Sachin B. Zanwar, Gajera P. Falguni, "Free radical scavenging activity of aqueous root extract of *Argyreia nervosa* (Burm.f.) Boj. (Convolvulaceae)", Journal of Natural Remedies, July-Dec 2009, Vol. 9/2: 216-223.

- 10. Gajera Falguni P., Movalia Dharmishtha A. and Gajera Keyur P., Development and Validation of HPTLC Method for Quantitative Estimation β-sitosterol in Plant Extract of *Phyllanthus reticulatus* Poir. In international journal of pharmaceutical formulation and analysis, March-2010, Vol. 2.
- 11. Annie Shirwaikar, Saleemulla Khan, Yogesh H. Kamariya, Bharatkumar D. Patel and Falguni P. Gajera, Medicinal Plants for the Management of Post Menopausal Osteoporosis: A Review, The Open Bone Journal, 2010, 2, 1-13.

CERTIFICATIONS

- 1. "General course in Intellectual Property Rights (DL-101)" conducted by Worldwide Intellectual property Organization (W.I.P.O.), Geneva.
- 2. "Patenting in Pharmaceuticals", organized by S. J. Thakkar Pharmacy College, Rajkot during 17th to 29th May, 2010. This was sponsored by AICTE staff development program.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Qualified Graduate Aptitude Test of Engineering (GATE) in the year of 2006, organized by Indian Institute of Technology (IIT), kharagpur with 87.33 percentile, All India Rank (AIR) – 1802.

LANGUAGES

Gujarati: Native language

- Hindi and English: Able to speak fluently and read/write with good proficiency